-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤倒时差
翻译: sharefans_笨 viola_cui 西皮jo 笑点滴 晓笛 2k-onami
校对: Mabb
赤焰战场 2
- Baby, check this out.  - A power washer?
- 宝贝 看看这个  - 强力清洗器?
We need one of these.
我们需要这样一台
Yeah.
对
- On the patio in the backyard.  - Yeah.
- 清理后院用得上  - 好
Should we go look at those window treatments?
我们去看看玻璃清洁剂吧?
No.
不要
Do you want one of these hotdogs?
你想要来一个热狗吗?
They're very good.
很好吃呦
Baby, you are a heck of a homemaker.
宝贝 你真是个居家好男人
You know that? But we could just go to dinner.
这样吧? 我们直接去外边吃晚饭吧
Well, you know,
哦 其实
if you don't make it...
自己动手...
You don't eat it.
丰衣足食
You know what? That's a great idea. What if I make you dinner?
对吧? 是个好主意 我给你做晚饭好吗?
I'm gonna go and get that, uh, grill. The big shiny one.
我要去拿那个 呃 烤架 又大又亮的那个
Will you get us some shrimp? The big jumbo kind.
你去拿些虾吧? 大包装的那种
Four down. Three over.
往前走四排 再过去三排的地方
Come back and find me down here. In tools.
然后回来这里找我 工具区
What the hell are you doing here?
你他妈来干什么?
You ignored my messages.
你不回复我的消息
I am happy.
我很快乐
You're desperate.
你很绝望
- I can make this work.  - Frank, you're playing house.
- 我这样挺好  - 弗兰克 你是在过家家
Look, I'm retired, okay. I'm happy. We are happy.
是这样 我退休了 好吧 我很快乐 我们很快乐
Frank... Frank...
弗兰克... 弗兰克...
You haven't killed anybody in months.
你已经好几个月没杀人了
That is not a bad thing, okay?
这不是坏事 好不好?
That's a positive thing for a lot of people.
对大部分人来说这是正常的
Kemosabe, I need you. They're coming. I can feel it.
独行侠 我需要你 他们来了 我能感觉到
You are driving me nuts, Marvin.
你快把我逼疯了 马文
Listen, if it makes you feel better, bring the girl.
听着 如果你愿意的话 可以带上那个女孩
I'm not gonna bring the girl anywhere, all right?
我不会带她去任何地方 明白吗?
Don't bring the girl where?
不会带我去哪?
Oh, we're just catching up.
哦 我们只是随便谈谈
Marvin's here. I just bumped into Marvin.
马文也在这 我刚好碰到马文
Where are we going?
我们要去哪?
No, come on. They're gonna close.
哪也不去 走吧 快关门了
Good to see you, Marvin.
很高兴见到你 马文
- Good to see you.  - Frank.
- 很高兴见到你  - 弗兰克
You know you want to.
你知道你想的
- No.  - Come on.
- 不想  - 行了
Last chance, Frank.
最后一次机会 弗兰克
I'm taking Sarah home.
我要带萨拉回家
Stay safe.
保重
- Well, I really wanted to be...  - Of course, it is, honey.
- 哦 我真的很想...  - 当然 是这样的 宝贝
You are never gonna be in danger ever again.
你再也不能身处险境了
We don't even know what happened.
我们都不知道是怎么回事
We don't know who's in there.
我们都不知道那里有什么人
How am I gonna protect you?
我该怎么保护你?
Hey. He was your best friend.
嘿 他可是你最好的朋友
Okay?
对吧?
Come on.
来吧
Wow.
喔
He still looks so lifelike.
他看起来还像活着一样
He's not dead.
他没死
Honey, don't do that. Just let your feelings out. Don't...
宝贝 别这样 哭出来吧 别这样...
No. Really.
不 真的
He does this a lot.
他干过好多次了
Really?
真的?
No, come on. Give me the pin. Give me the pin.
别 给我 把针给我 给我
Come on, sweetie. Let's go sit down. Come on.
行了 宝贝 我们去坐下吧 走
- Come on.  - I should kiss him.
- 来吧  - 我该吻他
Yeah, go ahead. Do you want to?
是 吻吧 真的吗?
Let's go sit down. Come on. Come on, sweetie.
还是去坐下吧 走 走了 宝贝
At this time, we'll open the floor to anyone
此时此刻 是否有人愿意走上前来
who wishes to say a few words about the deceased.
来为逝者讲几句
Babe...
宝贝...
Share a memory, perhaps?
或者 说说往事?
Perhaps, a poem. A song lyric.
再或者 念首诗 或者一首歌词
Anyone?
有人要来吗?
You can do it.
你可以的
Sir?
先生?
Marvin was
马文他
different.
与众不同
He was
他是个
a very good shot.
神枪手
Some would say that
有人说他
he was paranoid.
是妄想症
But you have to expect a little of that when the CIA's dosing you with LSD
不过中情局给你服用了超过十年的迷幻药
for a little more than a decade.
这情况很正常
He could wire a bomb
他布置炸弹的速度
faster than anybody I ever met.
比我见过的任何人都快
The good people of Moldova will always
摩尔多瓦善良的人们永远
be in Marvin's debt.
都应该记得马文的恩德
He was a really good friend.
他真的是个好朋友
Really good.
非常好
I'm gonna miss him.
我会怀念他的
Gonna miss him.
会的
- We have to move.  - Canada?
- 我们得搬家  - 加拿大?
High ground. Good kill zones. It's a little farm.
高地 很好的猎杀地区 是个小农场
- A farm? Like, to farm on?  - Yeah. Yeah.
- 农场? 可以 放牧的那种?  - 对 是的
Like, with crops?
还可以 种庄稼那种?
Yeah. It could be fun.
对 挺有意思的
Listen, babe...
听着 宝贝...
You know they say it's really important not to make big...
据说在经历过大的悲伤之后...
life-altering decisions right after a loss.
最好不要做重大的决定
If they can get to Marvin, they can get to you and they can get to me.
如果他们能追到马文 他们就能追到你也能追到我
Who are they?
他们是谁?
Go to the safe house.
去安全房
Look at me. Go to the safe house.
看着我 去安全房
I'll come find you, okay?
我会去找你的 好吗?
- I'm not leaving you.  - Listen...
- 我不要离开你  - 听话...
It'll be all right.
不会有事的
What is it?
你们是?
Mr. Moses...
摩西先生...
They want to debrief you at a Yankee White Facility.
海军罪案调查处要讯问你
Is that your sniper?
还带了狙击手?
You're flagged Retired Extremely Dangerous.
因为你被标记为"极度危险退休人员"
海军罪案调查处
Hi, there.
嗨 你好
Um, my client Frank Moses is here.
呃 我的委托人弗兰克・摩西在这
He's an American citizen being detained illegally without due process.
他是一名美国公民被未经司法程序而非法扣留于此
- You know what? That is a lovely blazer.  - Oh, thank you.
- 你选的吗? 上衣真好看  - 哦 谢谢
You're welcome.
别客气
I'm sorry, I have no idea.
抱歉 我不清楚
But let me get Mr Snyder for you.
我帮你叫斯奈德先生
Thank you.
谢谢
How can I help you?
我能帮你什么吗?
- Oh, hi, there. I'm sorry. What is your name?  - John Snyder.
- 哦 嗨 你好 抱歉 你叫什么?  - 约翰・斯奈德
John. You know what? I didn't get your name.
约翰 还有你呢? 我还不知道你叫什么
- Oh, it's Kelly.  - Hi, Kelly.
- 哦 我叫凯丽  - 嗨 凯丽
John...
约翰...
John... John!
约翰... 约翰!
Unless you want to end up like Kelly,
你如果不想跟凯丽一样下场
I suggest you tell me where Frank Moses is right now.
就马上告诉我弗兰克・摩西在哪
Now!
快!
In interrogation.
在审讯室
Ah!
啊!
I got a document right here that says that you have a special interest in the Cold War.
我这里有一份文件称你在冷战时期执行过特殊任务
We know that back in the day, you spent an awful lotta time in Russia.
我们知道那个时候 你在俄罗斯过了一段苦日子
I just need to know what you know about Project Nightshade.
我只需要知道你对"龙葵行动"知道些什么
I really don't know anything about it.
我真的什么都不知道
What the hell is that?
什么声音?
Small arms gunfire, 200 yards.
微型冲锋枪 距离200码
Watch him.
盯着他
100 yards.
100码
They're coming to kill us.
他们是来杀我们的
Get me outta these cuffs.
打开我的手铐
I can't do that, sir.
恕难从命 先生
You have the key, right?
你带着钥匙 对吧?
Hands up!
举起手来!
50 feet.
还有50尺
They're gonna kill us both, if you don't get me outta these cuffs.
你不给我打开手铐的话 他们会把我们都杀掉的
Come on.
来吧
Frank Moses.
弗兰克・摩西
You know, coming up through the ranks, you were my hero.
其实要论军功 你是我心目中的英雄
Given enough time, I guess everyone cracks.
不过岁月不饶人 再厉害也不得不服老吧
Huh, Frank?
对吧 弗兰克?
- Who are you?  - Me?
- 你是谁?  - 我?
Mmm-hmm.
嗯
I'm the guy the government hires to get information.
我是政府雇佣来获取情报的人
And I'm allowed to use any form of torture I deem fit.
而且我可以进行我认为合理的任何形式的刑讯逼供
And I will torture Sarah until you speak.
而且如果你不开口我会对萨拉用刑
Speaking of Sarah, I love watching her
说到萨拉 我喜欢看着她
shave her legs in the tub.
躺在浴缸里刮腿毛
Kinda reminds me of these Belgian mercs I met in the Congo.
让我想起了我在刚果遇到的那些比利时佣兵
They would skin people alive to get them to talk.
为了逼供他们会活剥人皮
And do you know where they started?
你知道他们总哪里开始剥吗?
Guess.
猜猜
At the ankles. Just like your Sarah.
从脚踝 跟你的萨拉一样
So...
那么...
You either give me the information that I need to know...
要么你给我我要的情报...
Or I'm gonna fillet your girl from head to toe with no mercy.
要么我毫不留情得把你的女人凌迟了
Awesome.
很好
Wow.
喔
Pretty good for a retired guy. But are you...
对一个退休人员来说身手不错 可是你难道...
1-2-3-4-5-6...
一二三四五六...
7-on-1 cuffed with no weapon good?
七对一 你还被铐着 手无寸铁也可以吗?
Son of a...
他妈的...
Go. Go, go, go!
上 快 快 快!
Shoot him, but don't kill him.
打伤就行了 留活口
All right, kill him. Spray it up.
好吧 打死也可以 包抄上去
Frank, this is your last chance.
弗兰克 这是你的最后机会
Fire.
开火
Get in there! Go!
进去! 快!
Shit.
该死
Marvin!
马文!
- You're driving me crazy!  - I brought the key.
- 你快把我逼疯了!  - 我带钥匙来了
You faked your death.
你又装死
- Gotta go.  - Let's go.
- 该走了  - 我们走
Gotta go.
走吧
You have no idea what you put me through!
你知道这给我惹了多大麻烦吗!
Oh! Thank God, you're okay.
哦! 谢天谢地 你没事
No!
不!
- What are you doing here?  - Marvin brought me. From the house.
- 你来干什么?  - 马文带我来的 从安全房
Has everybody lost their mind?
难道所有人都疯了吗?
- Marv, you don't bring a girl like that here.  - I had to see if you were okay, didn't I?
- 马文 你不能把那样的女人扯进来  - 我总要知道你没事 对吧?
Honey!
宝贝!
- I thought...  - What?
- 我觉得...  - 怎么了?
Remember when we had that conversation about how you were gonna lay low?
记得我们说过你不能参与这些吗?
You don't get to tell me when to lay.
你也没说哪些不能参与
I mean, I'm not saying that.
我想说 我不是那个意思
Stop. Just don't. Just don't... No.
别说了 别说了 别... 不
- You're mad at me now?  - You treat me like a china doll.
- 你现在生我气了?  - 你对我像瓷娃娃一样
Frank, can I give you a little advice about women?
弗兰克 我能给你一些关于女人的建议吗?
No! Absolutely not!
不能! 完全不能!
Listen, you gotta ask yourself,
这样 你应该扪心自问
what is a girl like that doing with a guy like you?
一个那样的女人跟你这样一个货在一起图什么?
It ain't for your looks.
肯定不是因为你长得帅
You know, I will shoot you. I will shoot you in the liver.
听着 我要开枪了 打烂你的肝
Adventure, romance, danger, activities you can share as a couple.
冒险 浪漫 危险 行动 这才是你能为伴侣分享的东西
It's about you lying to me.
是你骗我的事
Frank...
弗兰克...
I was very touched that you cried at my funeral.
你在我的葬礼上哭我很感动
That's not true.
没有的事
I didn't cry at your funeral.
我在你葬礼没有哭
I'm no crier.
我从来不哭
Ninety-six hours ago, somebody posted a document on the Internet
九十六个小时之前 有人在网络上发布了一份文件
that said you and I took part in an operation called Nightshade back in '79.
称你我曾经在79年参与过一个叫"龙葵"的行动
That's why you fake died?
所以你才会装死?
Yeah. The chatter went through the roof.
是 这引起了极大关注
So everybody's after you for something they think you know
所以所有这些追你们的人认为你们知道一些
that you don't even know at all?
你们其实并不知道的事?
Oh, my God! Spiders!
哦 天呐! 蜘蛛!
Honey, you need to go to ground and it's best I don't know where.
宝贝 你应该离开去一个我不知道的地方
Yeah, I'm not going anywhere.
不 我哪也不去
- Cash only. No calls. No contacts.  - Thanks. Look...
- 只花现金 别打电话 别联系  - 谢谢 这样...
I'm not hanging out in some bunker while you slink around and save the planet
你在外边溜来溜去跟幽昧的国际危险女性一起拯救世界的时候
with dusky international femme fatales.
我才不要躲在某个地堡里
- Dusky?  - Dark, smoldering.
- 幽昧?  - 幽暗 烟熏的意思
I know what it means, Marvin.
我知道什么意思 马文
It's hard to be the kinda person I have to be right now
有你在场的情况下
and do the kinda things that I'm going to have to do while you're here.
我做不了我自己 也办不成该办的事
This is gonna be good for us.
这会对我们有好处的
What are we doing?
我们要做什么?
Let's face it, Columbo, things were getting a little stale.
面对吧 可伦坡 一切都变了
Wow. Mommy just slapped Daddy at the dinner table.
喔 妈妈在饭桌上扇了爸爸一巴掌哇
Is there a human being in the trunk?
后备箱里有个人?
Yeah.
是
Who is it, Marvin?
是谁 马文?
He's a Senior Director of Military Intelligence.
他是军情六处的一位高级主管
I've been caramelizing his onions for a couple of days.
我已经折磨他好多天了
Caramelizing how?
怎么折磨?
With three tabs of acid and a lot of rats.
三勺酸液和很多老鼠
Dang!
啊!
五角大楼
Eleven people dead. Five FBI. And the SecDef wants a briefing?
11个人死了 5个是联邦调查局的 国防部长想要一个简报?
You were brought in to contain this.
你是干嘛吃的
Calm down.
冷静点
I can't believe this is coming back on me after so many years.
我不信这么多年了 这件事还会找上我
General, Moses and Boggs have been completely isolated.
将军 摩西和博格斯已经被彻底孤立了
The FBI is seeking them for the murders.
联邦调查局要以涉嫌凶杀逮捕他们
Homeland has been informed that they are officially domestic terrorists.
国土安全局已经正式接到通知 说他们是恐怖分子
Is that gonna work?
这样做靠谱吗?
Yes.
是的
The problem is with that document surfacing on the Internet,
问题是只要网上有那个文件
all the players will be coming after Nightshade.
所有人都会去追寻龙葵的下落
It'll open the book on this.
纸包不住火
I'm calling SecDef. We need to go public.
我要给国防部长打电话 我们得把这件事公布于众
General...
将军...
Nobody's going public.
没有人可以把这件事公布于众
We need a new plan for Moses.
我们需要为摩西制定一个新计划
I need you to approve a specialist.
我需要你批准一个专家参与此事
What? CIA?
什么专家? 中央情报局的?
It's been tried, sir. Didn't work so well for those guys.
我已经试过了 他们对付不了那些家伙
Han Cho Bai. He's the best.
去请韩秋白 他是最厉害的
Do it.
那就去吧
香港
Suit, too.
衣服也脱下来
Okay, he's clean.
好了 他没问题
Seriously?
没搞错吧?
Sit down, Mr. Han.
请坐 韩先生
Your security is impressive.
你的安保措施不错嘛
A business associate.
他是一个商业伙伴
Julio Alvarez Fernandes.
胡里奥・阿尔瓦兹・费尔南德斯
Very difficult to get close to.
很难接近
Of course, it must appear like an accident.
当然 这必须处理得像一个意外事故
Not a problem. Except for one thing.
没问题 除了一件事
Mmm?
嗯?
Mr. Fernandes pays better.
费尔南德斯先生出价更高
Yeah?
喂?
Who's the target?
目标是谁?
Oh, it's an old pal of yours. Frank Moses.
噢 是你的一个老朋友 弗兰克・摩西
Karma is a bitch, Frank.
报应到了 弗兰克
伦敦 军情六处总部
What is this?
这又是怎么了?
There's a watchword flag on a WikiLeaks document.
维基解密文件上有一个标志
It's coded Priority One Alpha Seven.
表示它是最高机密文件
- Something called Nightshade.  - Shut up!
- 有个叫龙葵的东西  - 闭嘴!
Get out.
快出去
Find me Victoria Winslow.
给我找维多利亚・温斯洛
Director Philips?
菲利普斯主任?
Um...
嗯...
I'm with someone right now.
我这里有客人
Keeping busy, I see.
看来你还是闲不住啊
Idle hands do the Devil's work.
游手好闲 造恶之源
Yes.
没错
I understand you can get close to Frank Moses.
我知道你能接近弗兰克・摩西
Yes.
没错
MI6 has a job for you.
军情六处有任务给你
If you want to stay alive, you're going to accept it.
如果你想活命 就接受它
It's time to choose sides, Victoria.
是时候选择立场了 维多利亚
Where do they teach you guys this stuff?
他们在哪儿教会你们这些东西的?
Manuals, mostly.
看说明书 自学
Mmm.
嗯
Some of this stuff you just can't teach.
一些东西是教不来的
Wow.
哇
Isn't this cool?
这不是很酷吗?
We're on a mission together.
我们一起完成任务
Do you have any idea how many people are trying to kill us right now?
你知道现在有多少人想要杀死我们吗?
You and I both know that this is where you belong.
我们都明白 这里才是你应该在的地方
Right here. In the thick of it.
就在这儿
Pussy Cat's right, Frank.
美人儿说得对 弗兰克
Here we go.
走吧
Watch your step.
小心脚下
What?
怎么了?
Oh.
噢
Come on!
拜托!
- Where did you get this?  - Um... Marvin.
- 这是从哪儿来的?  - 嗯... 马文给我的
- You gave her a gun?  - It is America, Frank.
- 你给她枪?  - 这是美国 弗兰克
Everyone else has a gun.
除了我大家都有枪
She has no idea what to do with this.
她根本不会用
I know exactly what to do with it.
我会用
Ow!
哦!
You don't give fire to a kitten.
别让小白碰火器
Why don't you just give her some dynamite, Marvin?
你怎么不再给她点炸药呢 马文?
No external safety on the Sig?
西格这枪没保险哈?
Tell him what you told me.
把刚才告诉我的再跟他说一遍
At the height of the Cold War,
冷战期间
Nightshade was cooked up by a rogue US general
美国一个将军炮制了龙葵
as a first strike capability against the Soviets.
想利用它对苏联进行先发打击
- That's it. Can I go?  - That's it?
- 说完了 我能走了吗?  - 说完了?
- You want a little pepper with that?  - No, okay! At the height of the Cold War,
- 想来点这个配胡椒吗?  - 不 好吧! 冷战期间
a megaton-yield device was smuggled into Moscow
通过外交邮件 一个兆吨当量的核装置
in diplomatic pouches, piece by piece, and then the weapon was lost. That's it.
被偷运到莫斯科 拆开来运进来的 然后这东西丢了 就这些
You lost a nuke in Moscow?
你们在莫斯科弄丢了一件核武器?
The scientist was Edward Bailey. That's it.
制造它的科学家是爱德华・白利 就这些
What?
怎么了?
I made a mistake.
我犯了一个错误
Edward Bailey was a genius physicist who built some of the greatest stuff
爱德华・白利是一个天才物理学家
during the Cold War.
他在冷战时期制造过了很多杰作
Neutron bombs, particle beam weapons, nerve gas. Excellent nerve gas.
中子弹 粒子束武器 神经毒气 非常厉害
He was a rock star of conceptual mass killing.
他是大规模杀伤武器方面的明星
They called him "The Da Vinci of Death."
他们称他"死神达芬奇"
We were the security detail assigned to getting him in and out of Moscow safely.
那时我们被安排去保护他在莫斯科的安全
What happened?
然后呢?
We thought he was secure. The Soviets got him with a car bomb.
我们以为他是安全的 苏联政府策划了一场汽车爆炸 抓到了他
It was my fault.
这都怪我
He's dead.
他死了
Run or fight?
我们是逃是战?
All we've got is this WikiLeaks page off the Internet.
我们只有这个维基解密网页
Out of a Paris IP.
从一个巴黎的IP地址发表的
Hmm. Paris could be anybody.
嗯 可能是巴黎的任何人
Wait. Wait. Scroll back down for a second.
等一下 等一下 后退一秒钟
- What is that?  - Oh.
- 那是什么?  - 噢
Uh...
嗯...
Coffee stain?
咖啡的污渍?
Mmm. Wine.
嗯 是酒渍
Frog.
青蛙
What?
什么?
We're okay.
没事
Your number.
是找你的
Yeah.
喂
MI6 has just given me a contract to kill you.
军情六处刚刚聘请我去杀你
Apparently, you're guilty of nuclear terrorism, murder,
很显然 你涉嫌核恐怖分子 以及谋杀
and you're number one on Interpol's Most Wanted.
并且是国际刑警的头号通缉犯
What did you say?
那你说什么了?
Oh, I said "Yes. "
哦 我说"可以啊"
You know, the money's good.
你知道 他们给的钱很多
And anyway, if I don't do it, somebody else will.
总之 就算我不做 其他人也会做
Oh, and you should know the Americans are sending someone also.
哦 你应该知道美国也在派其他人去杀你
Who?
谁?
Han.
韩
It's bad, isn't it?
糟透了 不是吗?
- Is that Marvin?  - Yes. And Sarah.
- 你身边那个是马文吗?  - 对 还有萨拉
Aw! Send them my love, will you?
噢! 代我向他们问好
They're driving me crazy.
他们要把我逼疯了
Marvin gave her a gun.
马文给她一支枪
- Was it loaded?  - Yes! Yes!
- 上膛了吗?  - 对!上膛了!
Are you being controlling?
你正被枪指着呢?
No!
没有!
You have to take chances in a relationship.
男女关系一定要把握好机会啊
You have to be supportive.
你得主动点
I don't need her to fit in. I just need her to be safe.
我不想让她参加 我只要她安全
Just rent. Dirty Dancing, tell her you love her.
去租张碟 "脏舞"就行了 告诉她你爱她
You know, it's important to enjoy life while you still can.
在你还能享受生活的时候就赶紧去享受
Victoria just accepted a contract from MI6 to kill all three of us.
维多利亚刚刚接受了中情六处委托 来杀我们
You don't think she'd do that, do you? Frank, you don't think she'd do that?
你认为她不会那么做的 是吧? 弗兰克 她不会那么做的?
She's a friend.
她是我们的朋友
Frank, what, are you stupid? You never took a contract out to kill a friend?
弗兰克 你傻吗? 你从没受雇去杀一个朋友吗?
She called to give us fair warning.
她打电话只是警告我们
Come on. There's one more thing.
拜托 还有一件事呢
Han just went number one.
韩才是最大的麻烦
Why don't they just dip our balls in honey
还不如直接把老二泡在蜂蜜里
and stake us to an ant farm?
塞到蚂蚁窝里去算了?
Come on.
快点
Whoa! Crazy old bastard.
喔! 疯狂的老混蛋
Frank, do you feel old?
弗兰克 你觉得自己老了吗?
- Not really.  - Me neither.
- 没有啊  - 我也是
I mean, crazy sometimes, I guess.
我有时候确实有点疯狂
Who's Han?
韩是谁?
Korean. Counter-intel.
一个跟情报局作对的韩国人
Frank put him in jail for a few years.
弗兰克把他抓进监狱关了几年
We should be super-scared of him, huh?
那我们就应该怕他了 是吧?
Yes. He is the best contract killer in the world.
没错 他是世界上最好的职业杀手
I've got a hit off an old alias, silent for almost 20 years.
我找到了一个销声匿迹近20年的身份
He's dodging watch lists.
他在逃脱追捕
Bingo. Private flight to Paris scheduled for 09:00 out of Teterboro.
没错 他明早九点乘私人飞机从泰特波罗去巴黎
Find their hotel. Get blueprints and workups on the day and night managers.
找到宾馆 查到分布图 和经理换岗的时间表
Have Vance meet us on the ground.
让万斯在机场等我们
新泽西州 泰特波罗
They're one floor down. Two adjoining rooms. Surveillance is almost up and running.
他们在下一层 两个相邻的房间 监视运行正常
This is going to be easier than I thought.
这比我想像的简单多了
Hello. Speaking.
嗨 请讲
Yes.
是的
- Where are they?  - They were here.
- 他们在哪儿?  - 刚才还在
They ordered room service at 1:00.
他们一点才定了客房服务
What do you mean, "The plane is prepped"?
你说"飞机准备好了"什么意思?
I think someone stole your plane.
我觉得有人偷了你的飞机
I'm really going to enjoy killing him.
我真的很期待去杀了他
Get me a gun that really hurts.
给我弄支强力点的枪
So how good is this guy?
这个人怎么样?
Han is the best contract killer in the world.
韩是世界上最好的职业杀手
Let's just say that Frank is in some very, very deep dog doo.
弗兰克的处境非常非常危险
- He's not gonna kill me.  - Yeah.
- 他杀不了我的  - 没错
- Nobody kills Frank Moses.  - Right!
- 没有人能杀掉弗兰克・摩西  - 对!
The people he really doesn't like, he tortures for a long time first.
对于不喜欢的人 他会折磨很久
Can we just focus on trying to catch The Frog?
我们能不能集中精力去抓青蛙?
Okay. What's the action plan for target acquisition and rendition?
好吧 目标捕获及处置行动计划是什么?
Marvin?
马文?
Quit teaching her stuff!
以后不要再教她东西!
Nice.
好极了
What do you think the most expensive bottle of wine in the world costs?
你觉得世上最贵的葡萄酒多少钱一瓶?
Chateau d'Yquem 1847.
1847年的依坤宫葡萄酒
Maybe five, six, maybe, bottles left in the world. It's pretty pricey.
也许世界上只有五六瓶 非常贵
Maybe we should get a bottle of that wine and try to catch The Frog with it.
或许我们应该找一瓶那个酒 然后带着酒去抓青蛙
巴黎
My God, this is so romantic!
天呐 这里好浪漫啊!
Come here. Keep your head down.
过来 把头低下来
But we have to go to the Ile Saint-Louis for gelato.
我们一定要去圣路易岛吃冰淇淋
I don't think so.
不行
Really? What about the...
是吗? 那么...
- Frank, is that...  - Mmm... hmm.
- 弗兰克 那是...  - 是她
Hello, Frank.
你好 弗兰克
- Have you seen her since?  - Nope.
- 你后来见过她吗?  - 没
God, I've missed you.
天呐 我想死你了
Who is she?
她是谁?
Trouble.
她是个麻烦
How are things?
近来怎么样?
Yeah, Frank, how are things?
对呀 弗兰克 近来怎么样?
Sarah...
萨拉...
This is Katja.
这位是卡塔亚
Yeah. Hi.
没错 嗨
I need to speak with you. Immediately.
我需要跟你谈一谈 立刻马上
What the hell was that?
这究竟是怎么回事?
Katja Petrokovich. Russian Counter-Intelligence.
卡塔亚・彼得洛维奇 俄罗斯反情报局的
I think we should hear what she has to say.
我认为我们应该听听她要说什么
Frank...
弗兰克...
You don't know the half of it. She and Frank were young.
你不知道之前的事 那时候她和弗兰克还很年轻
And he didn't have the slightest idea she was working for the Russians.
他不知道她在为俄罗斯工作
She's Frank Moses' kryptonite.
她是弗兰克・摩西的克星
I like you with no hair, Frank.
我喜欢你的光头 弗兰克
Bald men are so sexy. Virile.
光头男人很性感 有男人味
Wow.
喔
She's cute.
她很可爱
Where did you find her? Nebraska?
你们在哪认识的? 内布拉斯加?
- Kansas.  - Kansas.
- 堪萨斯  - 堪萨斯
So what was it you wanted to talk to me about?
你想要跟我谈什么?
I would like to believe that the US didn't plant
我不愿相信美国在莫斯科设置了
a weapon of mass-destruction in Moscow. But I don't.
大规模杀伤性武器 但我做不到
Why are you in Paris?
你为什么来巴黎?
We come every fall for Strike Season
我们每年秋天都会为了罢工季来这里
- and for the weather.  - Oh?
- 还有这儿的好天气  - 哦?
Well, the US seems to think you're nuclear terrorists.
好吧 美国好像认为你是核恐怖分子
Russia wants complete access.
俄方想要拥有它
You agree now or I'll hand you over to the US government.
你要么现在就同意 或者我把你直接交给美国政府
Can't we just kill her?
为啥不杀了她?
Excuse me for one second. Can I talk to you?
抱歉离开下 我能跟你说几句话么?
- What? Oh. Uh-huh. Sure thing.  - Come here for a minute.
- 啥? 哦 行  - 过来下
- You know, I was shocked.  - I got it.
- 你知道 我很震惊  - 我懂
Yeah, I know. She was kinda counting your teeth with her tongue.
我知道 她都用舌头数了你有几颗牙了
A little, yeah.
确实有点
Can she go now?
她现在能离开了么?
We don't really have a choice. We need her to help us.
别无选择 我们需要她的帮助
I promise there is nothing between us.
我保证我俩之间没什么
No, sir. This guy's not giving us anything.
长官 这家伙什么都没给我们提供
Website's been scrubbed.
网站已经关闭了
NSA intercepted a dispatch to the Kremlin from Paris.
国家安全局截获了从巴黎到克里姆林宫的一条情报
Moses is going after someone called "The Frog."
摩西正在追踪一个叫"青蛙"的人
The Frog.
"青蛙"
So they call him "The Frog" because he's French?
管他叫"青蛙"是因为他是法国人吗?
No.
不是
No, he poisoned the water supply at KGB headquarters
不 他之前在克格勃总部的自来水中
with the Amazon tree frog poison.
下了亚马逊树蛙毒
He must have been wiping those little tree humpers for years.
他之前收集这些树上小动物肯定花了不少时间
Incapacitated 1,600 people and left with every secret we had.
致使1600人瘫痪 还带走我们所有的机密
You know, the guy makes a fortune selling information.
这家伙一直靠卖情报赚钱
He knows so much even the US won't touch him.
他知道得太多了 连美国人都不敢动他
The hard part is gonna be taking him alive.
难的就是生擒他
- Superb.  - Wine is wine.
- 超好喝  - 酒就是酒
I want to buy American air defense protocols.
我要买美国防空安全协议
Why is it terrorists never appreciate Burgundy?
恐怖分子怎么就不懂得欣赏勃艮第?
Look, I don't think you know
听着 想必你还不清楚
who you're dealing with.
你在和谁打交道呢
Shh! Excusez-moi.
嘘 稍等下
Hmm.
嗯
Confirmed. It's him. It's The Frog.
确定了 就是他 青蛙
Just don't look at him, right?
别盯着他 对吧?
Well, just act natural.
动作自然点
And whatever you do, don't look him right in the eyes.
不管你干嘛 别直盯着他的眼睛
Check.
明白
Remember, don't look right at him.
记着 别直盯着他
Idiot!
笨蛋!
- Marvin, you all right?  - Yeah.
- 马文 你没事吧?  - 没事
All right. Get her outta here.
好吧 带她离开这
- When?  - Now!
- 何时?  - 现在!
Get a car!
弄辆车!
Is that...
那是...
Cut them off!
抢他们前面去!
This is not a good idea!
这主意不好!
She's not gonna get there first!
不能让她追到!
Sidewalk!
靠边!
- Yes!  - No!
- 好!  - 不!
Yes!
爽!
Happy trans, bozo!
玩我 笨蛋!
Don't you think we should let...
你不觉得我们应该...
Shut your pie hole, Marvin!
闭上你的嘴 马文!
Don't you think we should let...
你不觉得我们应该...
Hush!
嘘!
Incoming!
过来了!
Bastard! Sidewalk!
要命啊! 靠边!
What the...
天啊...
She's fine.
她真靠谱
Got him.
看到了
What are you doing?
你在干嘛?
Got him.
有办法
Look! What is she doing?
看! 她在干嘛?
I'm begging...
我求...
Yeah, yeah. I got this.
好 好 瞧我的
I so got this.
我一定做得到
I hate her so much.
我好恨她
You're wasting your time!
你在浪费时间!
You're going to regret this more than you can possibly imagine.
你们一定会为此付出代价的
Hey.
嗨
You know who we are?
你知道我们是谁么?
Yes, of course.
当然
Tell us about Nightshade.
跟我们说说龙葵
You think I'm going to roll over for you hegemonic Mickey Mouse-loving Americans?
你觉得我会投靠你们这些喜欢米老鼠的美国霸权主义
Leave Mickey out of it.
别把米老鼠扯进来
1947 Petrus?
1947年柏图斯酒庄?
Yes. That one's rather...
是 这瓶相当...
God's sake!
上帝!
1945.
1945年
Wait, wait, wait! That bottle...
等 等 这瓶...
How do we find it?
我们怎么能找到它?
Never! Nightshade was the plot of lunatics.
不可能 龙葵是疯子的一个阴谋
I used to be like you. Driven by ideology and fear
我过去跟你们一样 被洗脑被恐吓
with no love of what's beautiful in the world.
从不思考这个世界多么美丽和可爱
I can't trust animals like you!
我才不信你们这些畜生!
Do what you will.
随你们便
Death is easy.
死很容易
It's not about the destination. It's about the journey.
这无关目的地 而是旅程
Death is an art form in Russia.
死亡是俄罗斯的一种艺术形式
There are so many ways to take a man to bits.
让人生不如死的方法太多了
Shall we start with a Chechen facelift? Hold him down!
要不要试试车臣整容? 往下按住他!
Stop! Stop it!
停! 停！
This is how we do it.
我们就是这么来的
Please. You're so brave.
拜托 你那么勇敢
But you have to understand
但你要明白
we're doing this for the right reasons. And this...
我们做这些是有原因的 还有...
This isn't worth your life.
为此放弃你的生命不值得
You must have something to live for.
你肯定还生有所求
Art.
艺术
Wine.
美酒
Women?
女人?
Hey.
哎
Help us.
帮帮我们
We need this information.
我们需要这个情报
You'll be helping us save the world. Please.
你在帮我们拯救世界 拜托
Mmm.
嗯
You, I'll help.
因为你 我帮了
Excuse me.
让一下
Thank you.
谢谢
And you can suck it.
你没戏
Baby? Honey?
宝贝? 甜心?
Seriously? You hooked up with that?
认真的么? 你跟她搞一起了?
What a woman.
了不起的女人
Is that the same dress?
这两件裙子一样的吗?
They look the same to you?
在你看来它们是一样的?
No one ever called me Frank Moses' kryptonite.
没人叫过我是弗兰克・摩西的克星
Frank's crazy about you.
弗兰克疯狂的爱着你
I've never seen him afraid of anything except losing you.
我从没见过他那么怕失去你
What if I'm ruining his life?
可我是不是正在毁了他的生活?
Frank is a very simple creature with very simple needs.
弗兰克是那种头脑简单欲求单一的动物
Okay? It's killing,
好吗? 就只是杀人
eating,
吃饱
sexting,
一夜情
eating...
吃饱...
Killing, I guess.
杀人 我猜
What's your point?
你想说什么?
I can't believe you kissed The Frog.
我不敢相信你亲了青蛙
Well, I've kissed a lotta frogs.
我亲过很多只青蛙
- I got something for ya.  - What is it?
- 我有东西给你  - 什么?
The key to The Frog's security deposit box.
青蛙存款保险柜的钥匙
- From?  - Credit Lyonnais.
- 从哪弄的?  - 法国里昂信贷银行
Baby, I have a request.
宝宝 我有个要求
Uh-huh.
嗯
How would you feel about going out to dinner with me tonight?
今晚和我出去吃个饭如何?
- Hmm.  - It is Paris, after all.
- 嗯  - 怎么说这里是巴黎
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
好啊 太好了!
Stay here. I'll be right back.
待在这 我就回来
I need you, Frank.
弗兰克 我需要你
It's not a good time.
现在不行
One of our old assets has some real information.
我们有个线人提供了一些真实情报
He needs to meet with us right now.
他现在要跟我们见面
Nah.
不
Frank, what are you doing? She's kryptonite. What are you doing?
弗兰克 你在干嘛? 她是你的克星 你在干嘛?
- I'll handle it.  - Are you sure?
- 我能应付  - 你确定?
Yeah.
嗯
It's not okay. It's just some work.
不好意思 有点工作要做
- No, it's not fun.  - Go. You and Svetlana, you work it out.
- 别这样 多没意思  - 去吧 和你的俄国情人工作去吧
I promise you that I will be back in time for dinner.
我保证我准时回来陪你吃饭
I'll be back.
我会回来的
Keep her safe.
保护好她
What happened to us, Frank?
弗兰克 我们之间怎么了?
- Well...  - Hmm.
- 这个...  - 嗯
You betrayed me.
你背叛了我
You set me up. Tried to kill me.
你离开了我 差点杀了我
I tried to kill you.
我差点杀了你
They were good times, weren't they?
美好的旧时光啊 不是么?
You know, if you'd asked me to betray my country,
你知道么 如果你让我背叛我的国家
you know I would have.
我就不得不下狠心的
Yes, Madam.
好的 女士
My God.
天啊
You know, I looked you up once.
你知道么 我曾去找过你
You were in a bungalow in Los Angeles.
那时你住在洛杉矶的一间小屋里
There were roses out in front.
门前种着一大片玫瑰花
But I lost my nerve.
但我那时没勇气
So what do you want?
你想怎么样?
It was all about work with you, Frank. Rules.
弗兰克 记忆里都是和你共事 都是纪律束缚
Not rules.
不关纪律
Right and wrong.
对错
You know, it's harder for me not to follow orders.
你知道么 尽管我当时有自己的个人感情
Despite my personal feelings.
但我不能不遵从命令
But feelings don't matter any more than right or wrong.
感觉超越一切甚至对错
Orders matter.
但是命令却有对错
Orders?
命令?
Russia will handle things from here.
俄罗斯要从这拿一些东西
I'm taking the key, Frank.
弗兰克 我要拿走那把钥匙
I can't let that happen.
我不会让你拿走的
No?
不会?
I can't feel my arms.
我胳膊没知觉了
Enjoy Kansas.
在堪萨斯好好享受
Hmm.
嗯
He's out.
他晕了
He might be awake.
他好像醒了
Oh, good. So he can feel it.
正好 那他能感觉到了
Did you ever, ever in your entire career let yourself get drugged?
你整个职业生涯有被人下过药吗?
You still like her!
你还喜欢她!
And now she has the key!
现在她拿走了钥匙!
She doesn't have the key. She has a key.
她没拿走这把钥匙 她只是拿了一把钥匙
What?
什么?
I knew she would play him like a banjo at an Ozark Hoedown.
我知道这女人肯定会像弹班卓琴一样玩弄他
So I have the key.
所以我收好了
Water.
水
How long was I out for?
我是待了多久?
Some of it's his.
有一些是他的
Et tu Marvin?
马文 你也有份?
Style is the only constant in life, Frank.
弗兰克 潮流是生活中唯一不变的
We didn't come to Paris on vacation.
之前的假期我们没来过巴黎
Oh. Shopping's what I thought you did in Paris
哦 在巴黎我想你能做的就是
with your boyfriend's money
花男朋友的票子去购物来作为补偿
while you're waiting for him
当他被衣衫不整的 放荡的
to wake up from being taken down
俄国贱前女友迷晕放倒
by his skanky, slutty, Russian biatch ex-girlfriend.
你还得辛苦的等着他醒过来
So thanks. Thanks. Thanks for the compliment for the fur.
感谢 感谢你赞美我这件皮草
For telling me that I look nice in my dress. It makes me feel really good.
因为你说我穿这件裙子很美 我感觉相当好
And it makes me feel very loving towards you also.
这样也让我感觉好有爱
Why is she doing this to me?
她为什么要这么对我?
We can get a taxi over here.
我们打的过去吧
Frank, listen, I gotta tell you something.
弗兰克 听着 我跟你说些事
You have to start to learn to share your feelings to evolve your relationship.
你要学会分享你的感受 来挽回这段感情
Even if it seems uncomfortable at first.
尽管做到这点一开始会很不适应
Say you're pinned down in a firefight.
就说你身处枪林弹雨中
If you stay where you are, you're gonna die. Okay?
如果你原地不动 你就会没命 行吗?
So, you tell me, what do you do?
现在你告诉我 你要怎么做?
Make the run.
行动起来
Yes. You have got to make the run to emotional safety.
对 你必须行动直到感觉安全了
Huh.
啊
You dead yet, Moses?
摩西 你死了没?
Not yet.
还没
Where's my plane?
我的飞机呢?
In my ass!
在我菊花里!
- It's in an airport outside of Paris.  - What are you... Shut up!
- 在巴黎外郊飞机场那  - 你到底...闭嘴!
Let's get outta here.
快离开这
- Marvin?  - Yeah?
- 马文?  - 嗯?
Is that a stick of dynamite in your pocket?
你口袋里是不是还有一颗炸弹?
Yeah, but I'm saving it for an emergency.
是啊 我留着它是为了以防万一
Well, this is kind of an emergency, isn't it?
那 现在不就是万一的紧急时刻了吗?
The key I gave her is connected to a particularly nasty terrorist cell
我给她的那把钥匙与一个极其猖獗的恐怖组织有关
and their safe deposit box.
就是他们保险柜的钥匙
The French take this kinda thing pretty seriously.
法国人解决这类事很完美啊
That's enough.
够了
Put me down! Put me down now!
放开我! 立即放开我!
All right.
好吧
We gotta move quickly, Moscow will have her out within the hour.
我们得快走了 莫斯科会在一小时内放了她
For the love of Mike.
再见了美国情人
All right.
是的
I'm still not talking to you.
我没和你说话
All right. This is an MI6 report on Project Nightshade.
这是一份关于龙葵的军情六处报告
It's about the operative that placed the device.
是关于安置核装置的那个特工
They took him into custody and put him on ICE.
他们拘留并把他处以ICE
What's ICE?
什么是ICE?
Incarcerate, Cannot Execute. Who would they keep on ICE for 32 years?
监禁但不能处死 他们会把谁留在ICE长达三十二年呢?
- Come on. Gotta go.  - Come on where? Oh!
- 快 得走了  - 去哪? 哦!
How could she have possibly found us?
她怎么会发现我们?
Cause I called her and told her we were coming.
因为我打电话告诉她我们要来
I couldn't take the pressure of not knowing.
与其被偷偷干掉 不如面对面比较好
Why isn't she shooting at us?
为什么她还不开枪?
That should buy us 24 hours.
这样能使我们省下二十四小时
Hello, sweetie.
你好 亲爱的
You know, the next time you two make a plan like this,
下次你俩再制定这样一个计划时
you could at least let me in on it.
最起码要让我参与进来
Frank, you're compromising me.
弗兰克 你在怀疑我的判断力
Who knows what some girl is gonna squeeze out of you?
鬼知道你会不会昏了头告诉那女人?
Where'd you get the bodies?
你从哪找的这些尸体?
My freezer.
我的冰箱里
Come on. Wake up.
快起来
Yeah?
喂?
What the hell's going on?
事办的怎样了?
- Sir?  - Get anything from The Frog?
- 长官?  - 从青蛙那得到什么了吗?
No, he took some sorta poison before we really talked.
还没 在我们谈之前他服了种毒
I don't think he's gonna say anything now.
我觉得他现在什么都说不出来
You've got to find Moses and Boggs.
你必须找到摩西和博格斯
Mmm. Mmm.
嗯 嗯
Don't worry. I'm on the trail.
别担心 我在追踪
On your right, you see the famous Tower of London.
在你的右边 能欣赏到著名的伦敦塔
And shortly, we'll be passing under the Tower Bridge.
很快 我们将在伦敦桥下穿过
It's a fortress.
这是个城堡
It's an asylum for the criminally insane. He's in the ICE unit.
这是所专收精神病罪犯的精神病院 他在ICE间
That's an MI6 Alpha Level secure facility buried deep within that building.
那是被军情六处深埋在地下的最高安全设施
It's like a prison within a prison.
就像是一所监狱中的监狱
How are we gonna get in there?
那我们怎么到那?
She wants my head! She wants my head! It's a Papist plot.
她想要我的头! 她想要我的头! 这是个天主教徒的阴谋
It's her. It's that bitch Mary, Queen of Scots. She wants my head.
是她 就是玛丽那个贱人 苏格兰女王 她想要我的头
What are you doing? No! No!
你们在干什么? 放开我! 放开我!
Get me Cecil. Get me Cecil. I'm the Queen of England!
把塞西尔带来 把塞西尔带来 我才是英国女王
Don't take me to the Tower! I'll have your head for this, you bitch!
不要把我带到塔里! 你个贱人 我要砍你的头!
No! No!
不! 不!
"Uneasy lies the head that wears the crown."
"为王者无安宁"
They're plotting against me. All of them.
他们都在谋害我
There's a good queen.
这才是好女王
Stuff it, you old bat.
够了 老疯子
Thank you.
谢谢你
Not so much the "old," if you don't mind.
如果你不介意的话 还不是很"老"
I think it was really, really good.
我觉得我演的超好
I thought I was kind of channeling Bette Davis.
我都有点与贝蒂・戴维斯通灵了
Good morning. Dr. Jones to see prisoner number 17, please.
早上好 琼斯医生要去见十七号囚犯
Dr. Jones? Are you with MI6?
琼斯医生? 你是军情六处的吗?
Sadly, not anymore.
很遗憾 不再是了
Because I don't seem to have you on my list.
因为我没在名单上找到你
Bloody thing's not working. Why's that?
该死的这没用啊 为什么?
You're supposed to use...
你应该用...
Lay down on the ground.
趴在地上
Attaboy. On the floor.
好样的 趴在地上
Number 121. Oh, there it is.
一百二十一号 在这
Frank!
弗兰克!
Who are you? You're visitors? Who are you looking for?
你们是谁? 是客人吗? 你们在找谁?
We love having visitors, don't we, fellas?
我们喜欢有客人来 不是吗? 老兄们
Dr. Bailey?
白利博士?
Yes. Who did you expect to find here? Hmm?
你想找谁? 嗯?
- Sir...  - What?
- 先生...  - 什么?
I saw you die.
我看见你死了
Saw me die? Who is he?
看见我死了? 他是谁?
Frank?
弗兰克?
Frank Moses, my dear fellow!
弗兰克・摩西 我亲爱的老兄!
How are you, old sport? So glad to see you. So glad you came by.
你好吗 老兄? 真高兴能见到你 真高兴你能来
We've been expecting you. Haven't we, fellas?
我们一直在等你 不是吗 伙计们?
My God, Frank, why are you so old? Good lord!
天呐 弗兰克 你怎么这么老了 天呐!
- Sir...  - What?
- 先生...  - 怎么了?
You've been locked up here for 32 years.
你已经被关在这三十二年了
Come on, Frankie, you've gotta be kidding me.
得了吧 弗兰克 你是在逗我吧
Come on, put 'em up.
快 练练手
Thirty-two years. How extraordinary. Who are you?
三十二年 多离奇啊 你是谁?
Victoria.
维多利亚
Victoria! You should read this.
维多利亚! 你应该读读这个
Lenin. State and Revolution. Jolly good time. Stalin got it wrong, of course.
列宁的国家与革命 美好的时光 都怪斯大林乱搞
So where are we going, Frank? Are you taking us
弗兰克 我们要去哪? 你今晚要带我们去剧院吗?
to the opera again tonight? Is that where we're going, Frank?
弗兰克 那是我们今晚要去的地方吗?
The opera? We love the opera, don't we, fellas?
剧院? 我们喜欢歌剧 不是吗? 伙计们
Yes, the opera and the champagne and the strawberries all round.
是的 有歌剧 香槟和草莓
Sorry, my dear, what is your name again?
抱歉 亲爱的 你叫什么来着?
Victoria.
维多利亚
I'm sorry, it's the drugs
不好意思 这是他们一直给我
they've been feeding me, it's my short-term memory.
吃的药害的 我只有短期记忆
The drugs they've been feeding...
他们给我吃的药...
Something that's meant to keep us peaceful, I suppose,
应该是想让我们安静下来
or harmless!
或让我们不添麻烦!
Anyway, I know it's around here somewhere,
总之 我知道就在这附近
but I don't know where it is.
但我不知道具体在哪
Dr. Bailey, we need your help.
白利博士 我们需要你的帮助
- Mmm?  - Do you remember Nightshade?
- 什么?  - 你记得龙葵吗?
I'm sorry, I'm looking for my pipe and my St. Christopher medallion.
抱歉 我在找我的烟斗还有圣克里斯托弗像章
Boys gave it to someone.
孩子们总是乱拿东西送人
They were little boys, you see.
他们是小男孩
Now where it's gone... It's gone somehow.
现在它去哪了... 不知怎么地不见了
Um...
啊...
Oh, shit!
妈的!
Hey, Frankie, I'm over here.
嘿 弗兰克 我在这
I found it. it was in my pocket the whole time.
我找到像章了 它一直在我兜里
I couldn't find my damn pipe, though. But here it is.
我还是找不到我那该死的烟斗 但像章在这
Sorry, my dear, what was the question you asked me?
抱歉 亲爱的 你刚问我什么问题来着?
Do you remember Nightshade?
你记得龙葵吗?
Vaguely. It was some kind of a bomb, I believe.
模糊记得 是一种炸弹吧
Dr. Bailey, people are looking for that weapon.
白利博士 人们在寻找那个武器
People who want to use it.
人们想要使用它
Oh, dear. Yes, I do understand, of course. Believe you me.
哦 天呐 是的 我当然知道 相信我
But you know, I made many things for the Americans and
知道吗 我为美国人做了很多
Nightshade turned out to be a bit of a nightmare.
但最后龙葵可以说是一场噩梦
It was quite different. Turned out to be too dangerous.
太不一样了 最终证明是太危险了
So naturally, they had to lock me up in this place.
所以自然地 他们就把我关在这个地方了
And after what they did to me, I think it's perfectly natural
之后我觉得他们对我做的这些相当正常
I tell them all to go F off!
我让他们所有的人都滚!
MI6 tried to fake Bailey's death? Why? What are they hiding?
军情六处企图伪造白利的死? 为什么啊? 他们在隐藏什么?
You're gonna have to go. You're gonna have to go find out.
你得走了 你得查查了
You know they're gonna try and kill me.
你知道他们将会审讯然后杀了我的
- I'll call you from Russia.  - Do svidanya.
- 我在俄罗斯给你打电话  - 再见
Maintenance to Bridge 7.
注意七号通道
We got a breach in Maximum Security.
最高安全区域被入侵
Secure!
抓住她!
All right, what's so important?
什么事这么重要?
I just heard from my source at MI6 that Edward Bailey's alive and on the run.
我刚从军情六处得到消息说爱德华・白利还活着而且逃跑了
- That's not possible.  - This is bigger than a rogue general
- 这不可能啊  - 这比一个桀骜不驯的将军
and his unexploded ordnance. What don't I know?
和他的未爆炸武器的事更大 还有什么我不知道的?
The game has changed.
游戏已经变味了
The things Bailey knows are too dangerous.
白利知道的对我们来说太危险了
We can't let Bailey or Nightshade fall into terrorist hands, or millions will die.
我们不能让白利或龙葵落入恐怖分子手中 否则数百万的人将会死
Holy shit, it's real.
见鬼 这是真的
Unless we secure it, that weapon's going off in the middle of Moscow.
如果不采取措施 核武器将在莫斯科市中心爆炸
Right now, that's our best case scenario.
现在来看 那算是最好的情况了
Guys?
伙计们?
Ah!
啊!
Welcome, my friends.
欢迎你们 我的朋友
So, it is true. You're alive.
你真的还活着
Tell me, then, where is this device?
告诉我那东西在哪?
Who?
谁?
Work in progress.
还在进行中
I never thought I'd be smuggling
我从没想过能把
Frank Moses into the heart of Mother Russia.
弗兰克・摩西偷带进俄罗斯
Me, neither.
我也是
Oh, before I forget. Frank. Frank, a little something.
在我没忘之前 弗兰克 有点小事
If you are caught or Han catches you,
如果你被抓了或韩追上你了
suicide pill is a much better option than what you face.
还是服毒自尽比较好
You die with Russian smile on.
面带俄罗斯式微笑死去
Good luck. Do svidanya.
祝你好运 再见
- Mr. Bailey.  - Yes, Frank?
- 白利先生  - 怎么了 弗兰克
Is there any way you could tell us where you hid the nuclear weapon?
你能告诉我们核武器藏在哪里吗?
Look at all those cows, Frank. They're beautiful.
弗兰克 看这些奶牛 它们多美啊
Yeah.
是啊
Cows?
奶牛?
Hi! Yoo hoo!
嗨! 喂!
That's not good.
情况不妙
We have eyes on, Frank.
弗兰克 我们被盯上了
Where's my plane?
我的飞机呢?
They paid me to kill you.
他们雇我杀你
They didn't say I had to do it all at once.
他们没说让我一次就解决掉
This is not over, Moses.
摩西 这事没完
We're not over! It's not!
我们没完! 没完!
What's wrong with him?
他怎么了?
Wow.
哇
What is this place?
这是哪?
My first safe house.
我第一个藏身之处
Untouched, since 1984. Aw!
自从一九八四年就未动过 哇!
Fugu poison?
这是河豚毒?
Fugu poison is deadly stuff. Terrible death.
河豚毒是致命的东西 死的很惨
This your little gizmo? XKG gas. I invented it.
这是你要的那玩意儿吗? XKG毒气 我发明的
We tried to take out old Fidel Castro in 61 in Cuba.
我们企图除掉老菲德尔・卡斯特罗
That didn't work though.
但还是没能成功
Any tea, Frank?
弗兰克 来点茶吗?
Why does Han hate you so much?
为什么韩这么恨你?
Not enough hugs as a child.
他小时候缺乏关爱
Frank framed him for stealing state secrets.
弗兰克陷害他窃取国家机密
So he went from being a highly decorated counter-intel officer
所以他从一位高端反情报官员
to... to being a pariah.
变成了个贱民
What's ironic though, is that Frank actually created the circumstances
更讽刺的是 弗兰克给自己的生命
for his own death.
创造了一个巨大的威胁
It's poetic.
太富有诗意了
I ain't dead yet.
我还不是没死吗
Should you eat that?
那能吃吗?
Is that safe?
吃下去安全吗?
It's before they had that, you know, "sell by" date stuff.
按这上面的保质期来看 还没过期呢
Oh.
哦
So did you get to meet Castro?
你见过卡斯特罗?
Who?
谁?
Did you get to meet Castro?
你见过卡斯特罗吗?
Yes, I did, actually. About two weeks after Kennedy was assassinated.
见过 在肯尼迪被暗杀的两周后
Talking of which, Frank,
说起这个 弗兰克
I'm starting to remember more and more who I am
我慢慢想起自己是谁了
and who I was and the weapons I made.
做过些什么 以及我制造的武器
My God, it really is amazing.
天呐 真是奇迹
How efficiently those boys from MI6, may God bless 'em...
军情六处的家伙们真是有效率 上帝保佑他们...
But you know something, Frank?
就是这样 弗兰克
They really do throw us away. Don't they, old sport?
一旦发现留着我们没用了
When we're no longer convenient, I suppose.
就立即把我们处理了 不是吗? 老兄
As though we'd never given them the best years of our lives.
完全不在乎我们把最好的年华献给了他们
Bit of a joke, really.
开个玩笑
Yes, very strange.
是的 异常奇怪
Do you remember where Nightshade is?
你记得龙葵在哪吗?
I'm sorry, my dear?
能再说一遍吗?
Do you remember where Nightshade is?
你记得龙葵在哪吗?
Oh, yes.
记得
Now, this feels right.
现在这儿应该对了
It's around here somewhere. I'm sure this time.
就在这附近 这次我确信
Everything looks different completely.
一切都和以前完全不一样了
Maybe it's over here.
也许就在那
- It's been hours. Hours.  - Yeah, this is it.
- 都找了好几个小时了  - 对 就是这儿
Here we are.
到了
How are those Jimmy Choos working out for you?
穿着吉米・丘跑路舒服吗?(著名奢侈品牌女鞋)
The entrance is up there.
入口在这儿
Who's Papa John?
谁是棒约翰?
It's new.
这是新开的
Entrance to what?
到哪里的入口?
Secret tunnels through the old catacombs.
通向老王宫的秘密通道
Brezhnev used it to sneak his mistress in.
勃列日涅夫当年用来与情妇幽会
- In where?  - In there.
- 在哪?  - 就在这
The Kremlin?
克里姆林宫?
The weapon is in the Kremlin?
武器在克里姆林宫?
It's the one place they wouldn't look.
这是他们绝对想不到的地方
Jesus. Do you mind keeping it warm?
天呐 记着要保温啊?
You have no idea the damage you've done.
知道你造成了多大的损失吗
You kept one of our own locked up for 32 years.
你把我们自己人关了三十二年
I have kept the world safe.
我维护了世界安全
- If that weapon falls into the wrong hands...  - The weapon?
- 如果那个武器落入坏人之手...  - 武器?
You haven't the slightest idea.
你根本什么都不知道
You must let me call Moses.
你得让我打给摩西
He doesn't know what he's walking into.
他不知道自己将面对什么
You've had your chance. It's over.
你曾经有过机会 现在没了
I'm sorry, Victoria.
抱歉 维多利亚
Sorry, my ass.
抱歉个屁
They say you're a legend around here.
他们说你是这里的传奇人物
I've...
我...
I've never heard of you.
我从来都没听说过你
Must have been a bit before my time.
肯定是在我来之前
Well, you've heard of me now.
好了 你现在见识过了
How is it possible they never picked up the radiation signature from that bomb?
他们怎么可能从没发现炸弹产生的辐射?
That's the million dollar question.
这问题问得好
Hey, gang. This is new.
伙计 这是新的
What do you think is behind that wall?
你觉得这堵墙后有什么?
Um...
呃...
I think Russians.
我认为是俄国人
If anybody sees that hole, we're dead.
如果那个洞被人发现 我们就死定了
I'm gonna need you to help me to disarm the weapon.
我需要你帮忙拆除炸弹
Frank, somebody's gotta guard the door.
弗兰克 总得有人看着门
- No.  - But...
- 不行  - 但是...
You'll need this.
你需要这个
将军同志
这是二十分钟前在红场拍到的
搜索建筑 派部队支援
One more time.
再说一遍
Great. Great. What does that mean?
很好 很好 意思是什么?
"Gas leak. Maintenance is coming."
"煤气泄漏 等待维修"
- Good. And then they'll move on.  - And what if they don't?
- 好的 然后他们就会走开  - 如果他们没走呢?
- Want a gun?  - Yes.
- 要枪吗?  - 要
No. No gun.
不行 不要枪
Just don't move. You're a security guard.
不能动 你是保安
Don't smile. You can't smile.
不许笑 你不能笑
You just never leave your post. Okay?
你别离开你的岗位 好吗?
Nice.
很好
Two shots, here and here.
两枪 打这儿和这儿
Drag the body in there and repeat as necessary.
把尸体拖进去 有必要的话就多杀几个
- No safety.  - No safety.
- 枪没保险  - 没有
Frank, I don't like the Kremlin so much.
弗兰克 我不喜欢克林姆林宫
And I like being underneath it even less.
我更不喜欢在它的下面
Here we are.
我们到了
That's great. It's just like yesterday.
太棒了 恍如昨日
There's my wrench or crow bar. Look at this.
这是我的扳手也可以说是撬杆 看这个
There.
那里
Hey, look, chaps.
嘿 看 伙计们
That's my old pipe. I knew I'd left it somewhere.
这是我的旧烟斗 我就知道我把它落在哪里了
My dear wife bought this the fifth, 1969.
我爱妻买的第五个 那是一九六九年
It was our wedding anniversary. Oh, yes! This is, um...
这是我们的结婚纪念品 噢 对了! 这个 呃...
This is Nightshade, by the way.
顺便说下 这就是龙葵
There.
看那
- Is that...  - That's Red Mercury.
- 那是...  - 红汞核弹
Red Mercury?
红汞?
We were always told it was a Cold War myth.
人们都说它只存在于冷战神话中
Yes, they said it couldn't be done, but I did it. See?
是 他们都说这不可能 但是我做到了 看到没?
Frank, if that's Red Mercury, you can zip it up in a backpack
弗兰克 如果它是红汞核弹 那你可以把它装进包里
and take it on the White House tour. It's undetectable.
在白宫巡游 没人会发现
No signature. No fallout.
没有信号 没有辐射
This is a weapon that will entirely change
这个武器将会在一夜之间完全改变
the balance of international power overnight. Just like that.
国际力量的平衡 像那样
We're all gonna die.
我们都会死
On your knees.
跪下
Katja.
卡塔亚
No government should have this weapon.
任何政府都不能占有这个武器
Not yours. And not mine.
你的国家不行 我的也不行
I have orders.
我有命令在身
This isn't about orders. This is about right and wrong.
这与命令无关 这关乎是非
Don't.
不要逼我
Did you really come to see me in the States?
你真的有来美国看我?
Yes.
是
What color were the flowers outside my house?
那时 我房子外的花是什么颜色的?
Yellow.
黄色
我发现你一直站在这里啊
煤气泄漏 等待维修
我叫帕沙 回头一起喝一杯吧
好?
我想你也注意到我了?
What in the name of... Hey!
搞什么... 嘿!
What are you doing kissing this guy?
你亲这个人干嘛啊?
I didn't wanna kill him.
我不想杀他
What kinda stupid logic is that?
这是什么狗屁逻辑?
What in the Sam Hill is she doing here?
她来这干什么啊?
She's working with us again.
她又和我们合作了
Like heck she is.
那才见鬼呢
Why were you kissing that guy?
你干嘛亲他?
Kids, what happens in the Kremlin stays in the Kremlin.
伙计们 在克林姆林宫发生的就让它过去吧
You are gonna have to explain this to me.
你要和我好好解释这事
Hey, Comrades!
同志们!
Here's to more success.
为了更多的成功
Success.
成功
And saving the world!
还有拯救世界!
Saving the world!
拯救世界!
Na zdorovie!
干杯!
I got this. Right back.
我接个电话 马上回来
Hey.
嘿
Where are you?
你在哪?
Moscow.
莫斯科
He's a nutter, Francis.
他是个疯子 弗兰克
MI6 didn't lock him up because he created the weapon
军情六处把他关起来不是因为他制造了那武器
but because he wants to see it go off.
而是因为他想引爆武器
Hello, Frank.
嗨 弗兰克
That was Victoria, wasn't it?
那是维多利亚 是吧?
Telling you that I was some sort of a monster
她和你说我是个怪物
who once wanted to destroy the Soviet empire.
曾经想毁灭苏联帝国
Yeah. Very slowly.
好 慢慢转过身
That's it. Good boy.
没错 好孩子
Good. In you go.
很好 进去
Marvin...
马文...
Guns down.
放下枪
Weapons down. Very slowly.
放下武器 慢慢来
You planted the thing on WikiLeaks.
你故意把它透露给维基解密
Oh, yes, it was a cell phone taken from a guard.
是的 我从守卫那拿了个手机
I was just itching to get my revenge on MI6, you see.
我只是渴望能够报复军情六处
Frank, you were absolutely marvelous the way you found The Frog.
弗兰克 你找到青蛙太不可思议了
No one else could have found him.
其他人绝对找不到他
Jack?
杰克?
Sorry, Frank, I made a deal already with Mr. Horton for Red Mercury.
对不起 弗兰克 我已经拿红汞和霍顿先生做了交易
- Well done, Bailey.  - Thanks.
- 干得好 白利  - 谢谢
Nice to see you again, Frank. Pick up the guns.
很高兴又见到你 弗兰克 把枪都捡起来
Your country appreciates your sacrifice, Frank.
祖国不会忘记你 弗兰克
But your time's up.
但你们的时代过去了
Let's go.
我们走
It's time, Bailey.
是时候了 白利
Yes, it is time.
是的 没错
Very Interesting.
多有趣啊
Rogue American agents turned nuclear terrorists kill top Russian officer.
叛逃的美国特工变身为核恐怖分子 杀害了俄罗斯高官
Not good.
不妙啊
So long, Frank. So long, Marvin.
永别了 弗兰克 永别了 马文
Come on, boys, let's go.
来吧 伙计们 走吧
Easy. Easy.
放松 放松
Oh, please, let me take that from you.
让我帮你拿吧
I thought we were doing the debriefing in London.
我以为我们要去伦敦做任务汇报
Oh, we were. But since you're such a sick, twisted bastard,
本来是要去的 但既然你是这么个病态而又心理扭曲的混蛋
you're going to Colorado.
你要去科罗拉多
There's a secret facility there, it's about a mile underground,
那里有一个秘密的设施 在地下一英里处
where you will spend your remaining years having every bit of knowledge
你要在那里度过余生 你大脑的所有认知
plucked from that giant head of yours.
都会被清除
Really? Hmm.
真的吗?
And since we're speaking frankly,
既然我们都摊开说了
I should say that it will make your last 32 years
我就告诉你吧 那里会你会觉得之前被关的32年
seem like a vacation in the Caribbean.
像是在加勒比海度假
Cuff him.
给他铐上
Mmm.
嗯
Oh, I say.
我说吧
Well, well.
好吧
Bet you didn't see that coming. Did you, old man?
你没想到吧 老头?
I must say, I didn't. Jolly good.
我必须说 我真没想到 太好了
After you.
你先请
Thank you. Good morning, gentlemen.
谢谢 早上好 先生们
What did he say?
他说什么?
Ready.
预备
Do something. Do something.
做点什么啊
I love you.
我爱你
At least Han didn't get us first.
至少不是韩先抓到我们
Really? You're gonna bring that up right now?
不是吧? 这种时候你还提他干嘛?
Ah, there is nothing more sexy in the whole world
啊 世界上再也没有什么比一个美丽的女人拿帅气的枪
than a beautiful woman with an incredible gun.
更性感的了
You're such a romantic.
你真是个浪漫派
Watch your eyes.
小心
Close your eyes.
闭上眼睛
I love the way your toes curl right before you fire.
我喜欢开枪前你的脚趾这样弯起
Hopeless.
无药可救
Mmm.
嗯
Ah!
哇!
- Freeze.  - Shh!
- 不许动  - 嘘!
You know something? I don't think you ought to point that idiotic thing at me.
你知道吗? 我觉得你没必要拿枪指着我
You should really start thinking about your security protocol, don't you think?
你该好好想想自己签的安保协议是否包括丧葬费?
What the hell is that?
那是什么东西?
That, my dear boy, is an antidote
那个 孩子 是解毒剂
to the most powerful nerve agent ever created. Look.
世上最强神经毒气的解毒剂 看
Hello, boys.
伙计们 你们好啊
Hello, Mr. Davis.
戴维斯先生 你好啊
And you didn't see that coming.
你没料到吧
Did you, old sport?
有想到吗 老伙计?
I'm sure you wouldn't want to miss what's coming next.
我确定你不想错过接下来的精彩内容
It's a little antidote. Jolly good.
这是一点点解药 很好
That's right.
好了
Uh, uh, uh, uh.
啊
Good. Thank you.
很好 谢谢
Jolly good.
太好了
Honestly, two days, Frank, two days,
老实说 两天 弗兰克 才两天
and you're in front of a firing squad?
你就落到行刑队手里了?
Yeah. But look...
是 但是你看...
No. No excuses. You're better than this. It's pathetic.
不用 不要解释 你明明可以做得更好 太可悲了
Frank, an American military transport made an emergency landing in London.
弗兰克 一架美国军用飞机在伦敦紧急降落
Everyone aboard was found dead.
飞机上所有人都死了
Bailey has taken refuge in the Iranian embassy.
白利已经到伊朗使馆避难
The Iranian embassy?
伊朗使馆?
We've gotta go there.
我们要去那里
All right. Get 'em ready.
好的 让他们准备好
I'm gonna make sure we're cleared for takeoff.
我去确保下我们能起飞
If the world is here in a week,
如果世界就在一周内灭亡
I will meet you in the Turks and Caicos.
咱们在特克斯和凯科斯群岛见
Mmm-hmm.
嗯
And we will spend all night
我们整个晚上
- beneath the stars.  - Beneath the stars.
- 都在星空下度过  - 都在星空下度过
Mmm...
嗯...
I don't speak Korean!
我不说韩语!
You having fun yet?
你玩得开心吗?
I'll let you know when I start having fun.
我开始觉得开心时会告诉你
You betrayed me.
你背叛了我
I had no choice.
我别无选择
You'd have done the same thing, if you were me.
如果换作是你 你也会这么做的
How much is the US paying you?
美国付你多少钱?
20 million.
两千万
Are you kiddin' me?
你和我开玩笑呢?
I asked for more.
我要得更多
What happened to you?
你怎么了?
You used to be a good agent.
你以前是个好探员
Stop! Wait a minute. Listen, I need your help.
停! 等等 听着 我需要你的帮助
I know there's a part of you that wants to do the right thing.
我知道你内心还是想做正确的事情
There is a weapon that's gonna be detonated...
有一个武器将会被引爆...
Bullshit.
胡扯
It's not bullshit.
不是胡扯
There's a bomb headed for London right now.
有个炸弹正在前往伦敦
Eleven million people are gonna lose their lives if you don't help me.
如果你不帮我的话 一百一十万的人将会失去生命
All right.
好吧
Let's go.
我们走
This doesn't mean I'm not going to kill you later.
我可没说以后不杀你
I know.
我知道
I think the way to make a relationship work
我觉得要让恋爱顺利
is that neither of you give up who you are. Don't you agree, Marvin?
你们两个都不能放弃自我 你同意吗 马文?
Exactly. Exactly what Marvin says.
精彩 马文说得太好了
Falling in love is like jumping off a cliff. You just have to believe and let go.
相爱就像跳崖 你只需要信任并放手
My God!
天啊!
Are you okay?
你还好吗?
No, he's all right.
没事 他没问题
He's with us.
他是和我们一起的
We talked it out.
我们谈开了
Kill Bailey. Secure the weapon.
杀了白利 拿到武器
How hard can it be?
这会有多难呢?
Of course, the external security is very, very heavy
当然 外围的安保非常森严
but inside there are hardcore Revolutionary Guards.
里面是革命护卫队的核心部分
They are serious fanatics.
他们都是极端的狂热者
The whole thing depends on her.
成败都取决于她
You do realize, if they catch you, they will kill you.
你确实知道 如果他们抓到你 他们会杀了你吧
伦敦
I know this won't be easy for you, but don't worry.
我知道这个对你来说不容易 但是别担心
Okay?
好吗?
You know, I've been thinking about
你要知道 我一直都在想
you and me.
你和我
And I just...
还有我只是...
I got you something.
送你一样东西
Wow.
喔
You like it?
喜欢吗?
- I love it.  - Seven rounds.
- 太喜欢了  - 七连发哦
- Okay.  - Not yet. I'm not ready.
- 好吧  - 还不到时候 我还没准备好
Stop, no. Not right now. Wait.
停 不 现在还不行 等一下吧
If you don't do it, you're gonna blow it, all right?
如果现在不做 你就把这事搞砸了 知道吗?
Look at me.
看着我
- I'm gonna count to three.  - Mmm. Listen...
- 我数到三  - 嗯 听着...
I'm gonna count to three, okay?
我数到三 好吗?
- We can go back to the...  - In English.
- 我们还能回去...  - 我用英语数
- One...  - Not now. No. Wait.
- 一...  - 别现在 不 等下
Two...
二...
God damn it.
该死
Hi.
嗨
She's gonna get killed.
她会被杀死的
It's tough when they leave the nest.
这帮人离开老巢之后会很小心的
Frank, come on. A little trust.
弗兰克 想想吧 不管你信不信
She has talents you and I will never have.
她有你我都不具备的天赋
What talents?
什么天赋?
People like her.
人见人爱
If she lives, this'll be good for your relationship.
如果她能活下来 这对你们的关系很有帮助
You're right.
说得对
And if there's one thing I know, it's women and covert ops.
我自认唯一了解的事物 就是女人和秘密行动
That's two things.
这是两件事啊
No, grasshopper.
不 蠢蛋
It is not.
这是一回事
I wanna tell you a secret, Mr. Minister.
我想告诉你一个秘密 部长先生
Is she gonna make out with this guy, too?
她还想跟这家伙亲热?
Ohh!
哦!
What the hell was that?
你搞什么鬼?
Blowfish poison.
河豚毒
Paralysis and shooting pains will grip your entire body.
你的身体马上会感觉到麻痹感和枪伤的疼痛
And you will slowly asphyxiate until you choke to death
你会慢慢的窒息而死
while remaining fully-conscious, unless you do exactly what I say.
整个过程意识清醒 除非你照我说得做
I will die before I compromise my country.
来不及叛国我就会死的
Okay. We will drive you to your office where you will write a letter on official stationery
好的 我们带你去你的办公室 你要用官方信纸写一封文书来
denouncing the treatment of women in Iran.
谴责伊朗妇女所受的虐待
Then you will get your antidote.
然后你就能拿到解药
That's it?
就这些?
伦敦 伊朗大使馆
How may I help you?
有什么可以效劳的?
我想投靠伊朗
Ah. Dr. Bailey, my apologies for the delay.
啊 白利博士 不好意思推迟了时间
Professor Dombrovski has declared the weapon authentic.
邓布洛维斯基教授已经表明了这个武器是真的
And we're prepared to proceed.
而且我们已经准备好发射了
As soon as my money's transferred, Mr. Ambassador.
只要我能拿到钱就行 大使先生
Move! She's with me.
闪开! 她和我一起的
Arman?
阿曼?
He needs to go.
你得让他走
Okay, okay.
好的 好的
What are you talking about? Who is she?
你们说什么呢? 她是谁?
Sir, I'm sorry, you need to leave.
先生 实在抱歉 你得离开这
You need to shut up!
你给我闭嘴!
No.
不
What? What is happening here?
你们到底在这干什么呢?
Sorry. What are you doing?
抱歉 你在干吗?
Tell me what is happening here! Who is she?
告诉我 你们在这干什么! 她是谁?
Get out! When I say "get out," get out of here!
滚出去! 我说"滚出去"的时候 你就给我滚出去!
You need to go!
你得离开这!
You shut the fuck up!
你他妈给我闭嘴!
Where's the safe?
保险柜在哪?
What?
什么?
Where's the safe?
保险柜在哪?
Poo poo's coming.
便便来咯
24 Hour Plumbing.
24小时服务
Hurry. Emergency. Water everywhere. Come quick.
快 紧急情况 到处都是水 快来
Stop! Plumbers, wait!
停下! 水管工 等一下!
It's okay! This way.
没事! 这边走
Money received.
钱到了
Good show.
干得好
Let's see our friend here.
来见见我们的朋友吧
Would you lend me your knife, please?
能借我下你的刀子吗?
Thank you.
多谢
Sorry about the mess on the carpet.
不好意思弄脏了地毯
Oh, well.
哦对了
At this point, Jack... You don't mind me calling you "Jack," I hope.
这会儿 杰克... 希望你不介意我这么叫你
You must be beginning to comprehend
你一定开始意识到
the stunning totality of your failure.
你是彻彻底底的失败了
You can't give it to them.
你不能把它给他们
Oh, I've no more interest in giving Red Mercury
哦 比起我把红汞给他们
to these boys than I have in giving it to you.
我更想给你
Jesus.
天哪
Yes, it's a sad old world, you know.
是啊 我们还是在悲哀的旧世界
Anyway, that's only my opinion.
不管怎么样 我是这么想的
But the central point is this, Jack,
但是关键的是 杰克
you see, when men like you and those dickheads from MI6
你看 像你啊 或者军情六处 或者中情局的这些混蛋
or CIA or whatever sewers you came from.
不管你们从哪个部门来的
When you take away not only my life
当你们不仅要杀我
but the innocent lives of my dear beloved wife Natasha
还要杀我深爱但无辜的妻子娜塔莎
and my little boy, who was only six, you see. Yes.
还要杀我六岁的小儿子的时候 看看吧 是啊
I mean, what can I say?
我还能说什么?
When you mess with me, buddy,
你们既然惹了我 老弟
this is what you get.
这就是你的下场
Go to hell, old man.
见鬼去吧 老不死的
Fare thee well, patriot.
再见吧 爱国英雄
Boom.
砰
Now what's next?
下一步该什么了?
Ah, Washington.
啊 华盛顿
Baby, hey.
宝贝 嘿
Are you okay?
你还好吗?
Hah!
哈!
Awesome!
牛!
Oh, shit.
哦 妈的
- Is that it?  - It's counting down, Frank.
- 就那个玩意儿?  - 正在倒计时 弗兰克
Shut it Off. Right?
关掉它 好吗?
Shut... Yeah. With what? Acupressure?
关... 好啊 怎么关? 声控啊?
- I don't know.  - Well, why is it my responsibility?
- 我不知道  - 那为啥让我干呢?
Just do something.
快做点什么吧
With my Mr. Chemistry set?
就凭我的破化学?
I don't know what I'm doing. You want me to push a button?
我不知道该怎么做 你想让我去按按钮?
Bailey's loose and the bomb's ticking.
白利跑了 炸弹开始计时了
Wait. Excuse me, ma'am.
等一下 劳驾女士
Hello, I have an appointment.
你好 我有个约会
Gun!
枪!
Get that bomb outta here.
把炸弹拿走
- Drop it now, darling. That's right.  - My gun!
- 把它扔下 亲爱的 没错  - 我的枪!
Press the button. Ground floor.
按下按钮 下楼
Marvin, let's go!
马文 快走!
Jolly good show.
干得真漂亮
Bollocks.
妈的
You really drive this ridiculous thing?
你真要开这破玩意儿?
Can you shoot?
你能射击吗?
We need eyes, Francis.
你得引导我们一下 弗兰克
Come on, Frank. Forty minutes.
来吧 弗兰克 我们还有四十分钟
Marvin, how ya doin' back there?
马文 你在后面干得怎么样?
I can't talk to you right now.
我现在不能和你说话
How is it?
伤口如何?
It's fine.
没什么事
Shit!
妈的!
Show me something.
给我秀一下
Victoria,
维多利亚
I got eyes on. Bailey's heading for the M4.
我正在观察 白利要上M4号高速公路
Got it.
收到
Got it!
搞定!
This one should stop it and this one should detonate it.
这条线可能会止爆 这一条可能会引爆
It's fifty-fifty, Frank.
各百分之五十的几率 弗兰克
Wait!
等下!
That's weird.
不对头啊
Do you have any idea what you're doing?
你知道你在干什么吗?
Wait, wait! Wait!
等下 等等! 等等!
Stop cutting wires!
别剪了!
I knew we were gonna die!
我早知道我们要死了!
- Ready to kill this son of a bitch?  - Abso-bloody-lutely.
- 准备好干掉这个狗娘养的了吗?  - 必 须 的
Damn it!
妈的!
Trouble.
糟了
Marvin!
马文!
Frank, it's two pedals and two sticks.
弗兰克 踩两个踏板 控制两个操纵杆
Okay.
好的
Damn it! We missed him. He's going into the airport.
妈的! 我们跟丢了 他正在去机场的路上
Go get him!
去抓他!
- Well, where are you?  - In trouble.
- 好的 你们在哪?  - 遇到点麻烦
Turn back! You are in restricted airspace.
请掉头! 你们正处在禁飞区
Frank, they're gonna blow us outta the sky.
弗兰克 他们打算击落我们
I wouldn't worry about that.
无所谓啊
The engine's shutting down.
本来引擎就要熄火了
Mayday! mayday!
求救! 求救!
Frank!
弗兰克!
I knew we were gonna die!
我早知道我们要死了!
This is your last warning!
最后一次警告!
Oh, please, tell me you're not crashing with a weapon of mass destruction.
拜托 告诉我你们坠毁的时候没有带着大规模杀伤性武器吧
No, Frank, no.
不 弗兰克 不
Oh, God.
天啊
You okay back there, Marvin?
你在后面还好吧 马文?
It wasn't exactly a three-point landing, Frank.
这可不是个完美的三点降落 弗兰克
How's the bomb doing?
炸弹怎么样了?
I can't stop it.
我无法阻止它
We gotta get it outta here.
我们得把它带出这
Hey! Hey!
嘿! 嘿!
Get outta the car.
给我出来
Hello, Frank.
你好啊 弗兰克
Welcome aboard.
欢迎登机
Always the good soldier, aren't you?
你一直是个好大兵 不是吗?
Stalemate.
这是个僵局
How will you take him out and not shoot her first?
怎么才能不伤害她而又干掉他呢?
Frank, it's okay.
弗兰克 没关系的
You can shoot. It's okay.
你能开枪 没关系的
Put the gun down.
把枪放下
Put the gun down!
给我把枪放下!
Drop the gun!
扔地下!
Put the gun down, Frankie.
把枪放下 弗兰克
Thank you.
多谢
Pretty smart.
你真明智
So love does conquer all.
可见爱可以战胜一切
Go to your golden warrior.
走向你的黄金武士
That's a good girl.
真是个好女孩
Aw!
啊!
Come here.
过来
Ah! It's so sweet.
啊! 真幸福
Now leave the plane. Take Nightshade with you.
现在下飞机 带着龙葵
Bye, Frank.
再见了 弗兰克
Sweet dreams.
好梦哦
Why didn't you just shoot me?
你为什么不开枪?
- What happened?  - I couldn't disarm it.
- 出什么事了?  - 我无法解除炸弹
Oh, crap.
妈的
Marvin,
马文
it's going to detonate?
快爆炸了?
Yeah.
是的
Put your arms around me.
抱着我
Oh...
哦...
I didn't see that one coming.
出我所料
There's something you don't see every day.
这可不是每天都能看到的
You put the bomb on the plane.
你把炸弹放在飞机上了
And, um, you didn't think to mention that?
而且 嗯 你还不打算告诉我?
You blew up my plane.
你炸了我的飞机
Sorry.
对不起
I was wrong? So we're not even gonna die?
我错啦? 我们不会死了吗?
Not yet.
目前不会
I was actually starting to like you. I was even thinking about not killing you.
我真的开始有点喜欢你了 我甚至不打算杀你了
This is what happens when you try to save the world.
当你试图拯救世界的时候 这是理所当然的
Han. Han, you can't
韩 韩 这事儿
- put a price on these things.  - Uh-uh.
- 没法用钱算的  - 不 不
You owe me 30 million for the plane. And 20 for not killing you.
你欠我三千万的飞机钱 还有两千万不杀你的钱
You're a dead man, Moses.
你死定了 摩西
Thanks for your help.
谢谢你
Really.
真的
You think he means it?
你觉得他是认真的吗?
Nah, he's a nice guy.
没 他是个好小伙
I mean it, Frank!
我是认真的 弗兰克!
All right.
好吧
Aw!
啊!
They're going to be right as rain.
他们会非常幸福的
He made the run to emotional safety.
话说他真能提供一个安全的港湾
So...
那么...
I did hear about this job in Caracas.
我听说在加拉加斯有份工作
And?
然后呢?
Don't look at me. She's your girlfriend.
别看我 她是你的女朋友
Oh.
哦
Come on.
走吧
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 景鲤倒时差
翻译: sharefans_笨 viola_cui 西皮jo 笑点滴 晓笛 2k-onami
校对: Mabb